The simulator data consists primarily of images.
シミュレーターデータは主に画像で構成されています
Before I start using this data to train a model,
このデータをモデルのトレーニングに使用する前に
I'd like to look at those images.
それらの画像を見てみましょう
I'll start by opening driving_log.csv.
まずdriving_log.csvを開きます
Each line in this file represents a point in time
このファイルの各行はトレーニングデータ内のある時点を表し
during my training lap, and each line has seven tokens.
各行にはトークンが7つあります
I'm going to add labels to each column
各行の内容をわかりやすくするため
here so it's easier to see what each line represents.
各列にラベルを追加します
The first three tokens in each line
各行の最初の3つのトークンは
are paths to images, one each for cameras
車両のフロントガラスの
mounted on the center, left, and right of the vehicle's
左右と中央に取り付けられた
windshield.
カメラの各画像のパスです
The next four tokens are measurements for steering,
次の4つのトークンはステアリング スロットル
throttle, brake, and speed.
ブレーキ 速度の測定値です
The steering measurements range between negative 1 and 1.
ステアリングの測定範囲は-1～1です
The throttle measurements range between 0 and 1.
スロットルの測定範囲は0～1です
The brake measurements seem to all be 0,
ブレーキの測定値はすべて0で
and the speed measurements range from 0 to 30.
速度の測定範囲は0～30です
The throttle, brake, and speed data
スロットル ブレーキ 速度のデータはすべて
could all be useful for training the network,
ネットワークのトレーニングに役立ちますが
but for now, I'm going to ignore them.
今は無視しておきます
I'll start by using the images as the feature
まずは画像を特徴量セットとして使用し
set and the steering measurements as the label set.
ステアリングの測定値をラベルセットとして使用します
Then I'll use the images to train the network
さらに画像をネットワークのトレーニングに使用して
to predict the steering measurements.
ステアリング測定値を予測します
This is the very first image in the data set.
これはデータセットの最初の画像です
It's taken from a camera mounted in the center
フロントガラスの中央に設置された
of the windshield, and I can see the hood of the car peeking out
カメラの撮影画像であり
from the bottom of the image.
下の方にボンネットが見えます
The image is 160 pixels wide by 320 pixels high,
画像の幅は160ピクセル 高さは320ピクセルです
and of course, it's three channels deep
RGB画像なので深さは
because it's an RGB image.
3チャンネルです
The top portion of the image seems
画像の上部には 丘や木々、空など
to capture hills and trees and sky, elements
モデルの邪魔になりそうな要素が
that might distract the model more than help it.
含まれています
At some point, it might make sense
ある時点で画像の上部を
to crop off that top portion of the image.
切り取る方がいいでしょう
Here are the left and right images
これはCSVファイルの最初の行にある
that correspond to that center image for the very first line
中央の画像に対応する
in the CSV file.
左右の画像です
All of these images capture a similar scene
すべて似たようなシーンですが
but from slightly different positions.
位置が少しずつ異なります
You might wonder why the simulator gives us three camera
シミュレーターはなぜ各時点のカメラショットを
shots for each point in time.
3枚ずつ提供するのでしょうか
The reason is that we can use these camera shots to help
それは これらのカメラショットが
us generalize the model.
モデルの一般化に役立つからです
Effectively, we can pass these images
これらの画像をネットワークに渡すと
to the network to teach the network what
ネットワークは車両が道路の中心から外れているとみなし
it looks like to be off the center of the road
中央に戻るための
and how to steer to get back to the center.
ステアリング操作を行います
I'll talk more about this later.
これは後で詳しく説明します